Jules Bledsoe papers, Inclusive: 1918-1943, Bulk: 1940-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Jules Bledsoe papers
Inclusive: 1918-1943, Bulk: 1940-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2086
Bledsoe, Jules
8 document boxes and 12 oversize boxes.
The Jules Bledsoe papers consists of manuscripts collected by Jules (Julius) Bledsoe during the course of his musical career. These papers contain correspondence, diaries, financial papers, photographs, music, publicity materials, and other printed materials from his life and work.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Unknown.
Biography/Profile
Julus Bledsoe was born as Julius Lorenzo Cobb Bledsoe on December 29, 1898, in Waco, Texas. At five years old, he gave his first public vocal performance. Bledsoe originally wanted to pursue a medical career, but instead began studying music under Luigi Parisotti. After years of musical study, including degrees from Bishop College in Marshall, Texas, Virginia Union University in Richmond, Virginia, Columbia University in New York City, and time in Paris, France, Bledsoe made his concert debut in New York City at twenty-three years old.
Bledsoe adopted the stage name “Jules Bledsoe” early in his career, and was commonly called by that name for the rest of his life. His long literary career included composing and performing music, acting in plays and operas, and writing poems. Bledsoe’s work took him around the world, with performances in France, United Kingdom, Norway, Italy, and back to New York City in vaudeville, radio, and television.
Bledsoe played in many productions, including “Showboat,” “Aida,” “Emperor Jones,” “Deep River,” “Abraham’s Bosom,” and others. His signature song was considered to be “Old Man River,” which he sang in most concerts he gave. Bledsoe also wrote and performed his own songs and operas, which included folk songs, spirituals, patriotic songs, and operas.
Jules Bledsoe’s contributions to his art went beyond his musical skill. He was the first African-American to perform with a United States opera company in America, in addition to performing in operas around the world. Bledsoe was also known as a multilingual singer, proficient in English, Italian, French, German, and Yiddish by 1936.
Jules Bledsoe also owned a resort in New York’s Catskill Mountains open only to African Americans. Called “Jessie’s Manna Farms,” it is unknown how much profit he made from this side business.
During World War II, Jules Bledsoe assisted in the war effort by giving a war bonds tour around the United States. During one stop in Waco, Texas, his performance was so well received by the 2,500 people in attendance that he gave multiple encores for more than an hour after his show ended.
Jules Bledsoe died on July 14, 1943, in Hollywood, California from a cerebral hemorrhage. Noted Baylor University scholar and head of the English Department, Dr. J.A. Armstrong, spoke at his funeral. Jules Bledsoe is buried in Greenwood Cemetery, Waco, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Jules Bledsoe papers begin in 1918 and conclude in 1943 with Bledsoe’s death. These records include business and personal correspondence, diaries, financial papers, photographs, and an extensive collection of music. Many original musical, oratorical, and poetic compositions by Bledsoe are also present. Also included are such materials as press releases, programs, repertoire sheets, travel documents, and other mementos which Bledsoe collected throughout his career both in the United States and in Europe.
Arrangement
The Jules Bledsoe papers are arranged in 8 series: I. Correspondence, II. Financial Documents, III. Literary Productions, IV. Legal Documents, V. Photographic Material, VI. Music Manuscripts, VII. Oversize Materials, VIII. Media Recordings. A detailed listing of Bledsoe’s original music present in the collection is provided in Appendix A.
Prior processing had used the phrase “(last name) first name” to describe folders sorted by person, such as Bledsoe (Jules). This style of designation was retained.
Different parts of the collection were in various stages of organization at the time of processing. The music manuscripts were the most organized, but almost everything else had no discernable housing organization before this finding aid was written.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2086. Acquired 1973-05-00
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Irene Cobb papers, Inclusive: 1886-1991, Bulk: 1960-1989
Smith-Cobb Family collection, Inclusive: 1861-1968, Bulk: 1948-1965
[Waco] New Hope Baptist Church records, Inclusive: 1875-1988, Bulk: 1922-1985
Related references
"Jules Bledsoe Heads 'Emperor Jones' Tour." Dallas Morning News, 1934 September 2.
"Negro Artist to Sing for British War Aid." Dallas Morning News, 1941 April 1.
"Negro Who Started Old Man River Buried on Brazos." Dallas Morning News, 1943 July 22.
Plunkett, Virginia. "Jules Bledsoe Remembered at Ceremony." Waco Tribune-Herald, 1984 March 4.
"'Showboat' to be Heard on Air Thursday." The Afro-American, 1932 October 8.
Tolbert. "'Musical Grave' Stirs Controversy." Dallas Morning News, 1968 June 20.
Tolbert. "'Musical Marker' for Jules Bledsoe." Dallas Morning News, 1968 January 4.
Tolbert. "Musical Notes Wrong at Grave?" Dallas Morning News, 1968 May 29.
Tolbert. "Great Singer's Grave Lost Among the Weeds." Dallas Morning News, 1972 August 6.
Cobb, Naomi. Jules Bledsoe Biography. Smith-Cobb Family Collection, The Texas Collection, box 23, folder 10.
Geary, Lynnette Geary. "Bledsoe, Julius Lorenzo Cobb." Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2013 November 8.
Geary, Lynnette. “Jules Bledsoe: The Original ‘Ol’ Man River.’” The Black Perspective in Music 17 (1989): 27-54.
Geary, Lynnette. “Jules Bledsoe’s Voice Still Rings.” Waco History Project. Accessed 2020 December 4.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Bledsoe, Jules, 1898-1943.
Subjects
African American entertainers -- Europe.; African Americans -- Music.; Legal documents.; Notes (documents); Photographs.; Singers -- Texas -- Waco.; Vocal music.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Civilian relief.
Genres
Correspondence.; Financial records.
- Correspondence, 1918-1944, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Unknown.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence to and from Jules Bledsoe about his public performances, his personal life, the resort farm he ran in New York (Jessie's Manna Farms), and other facets of his life and career. Many of the letters are to or from Adrian Frederick Huygens, Bledsoe's longtime agent, who went by Freddy.
  - Correspondence, 1918-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1935 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1939 January-May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1939 June-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1940 January (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1940 February-March (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: April-October 1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1940 November-December (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1941January 4-9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1941 January 10-17 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1941 January 18-23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1941 January 24-31 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1941 February 1-11 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1941 February 12-28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1941 March (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1941 April 1-23 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1941 April 24-30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1941 May-June 14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1941 June 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1941 July-August 4 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1941 August 6-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1941 September-October 7 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1941 October 9-31 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1941 November-December 5 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1941 December 6-30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1942 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1942 February (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1942 March (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1942 April (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1942 May (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1942 June 1-25 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1942 June 26-30 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1942 July 2-August 7 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1942 August 26-September 29 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1942 October 3-November 18 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1942 November 20-December (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1943 January-February (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1943 March-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (1 of 3), undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (2 of 3), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (3 of 3), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Scrapbook, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Financial Documents, 1918-1942, undated; 2
  This series contains financial items from Jules Bledsoe. Many of them have to do with running Jessie's Manna Farm.
  - Bank Statements, Checks, 1930-1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements: Jessie’s Manna Farms (1 of 3), 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements: Jessie’s Manna Farms (2 of 3), 1928-1932 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements: Jessie’s Manna Farms (3 of 3), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Tax documents, 1932-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bills, Receipts, Notes (1 of 2), 1918-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bills, Receipts, Notes (2 of 2), 1941-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Literary Productions, 1915-1976, undated; 3
  This series contains literary items written by or about Jules Bledsoe. Notable items include a handwritten biographical manuscript about Bledsoe written by his aunt, Naomi Cobb. There are also many programs from Bledsoe's performances, pamphlets on Jessie's Manna Farm, and other literary items.
  - Journals, 1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Programs, 1916-1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1943-1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Programs, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (1 of 3), 1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (2 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (3 of 3), 1936-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: non-personal, 1936-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Essays, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Orations, Poems, Plays (1 of 5), 1941, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Orations, Poems, Plays (2 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Orations, Poems, Plays (3 of 5), 1916, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Orations, Poems, Plays (4 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Orations, Poems, Plays (5 of 5), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Plays: “John Henry”, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Plays: “Showboat”, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Biographies: Cobb (Naomi) (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Biographies: Cobb (Naomi) (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Autobiographies, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Musical Repertoire, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Essays: Labor Bulletin of Aberdeen, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Manuscripts: Music Venues, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Books: Handbook of Freemasonry, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Queen Wilhelmina Fund, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Broadsides and Flyers, 1943, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Handwritten, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Handwritten, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Handwritten, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Handwritten, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brochures, Flyers: Jessie’s Manna Farms, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts: Identification, 1935-1942 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts: Obituary Book, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sketches, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Legal Documents, 1934-1942; 4
  This series contains various legal documents having to do with Jules Bledsoe's life and music career.
  - Inventories, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Insurance Policies (1 of 2), 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Insurance Policies (2 of 2), 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Contracts (1 of 2), 1934-1941 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Contracts (2 of 2), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Photographic Materials, 1935-1938, 1941-1943, undated; 5
  This series contains photographs of Bledsoe, primarily during his time traveling the world as an international opera star. There are also extensive publicity pictures of him in the various roles he played on stage.
  - General (1 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General (2 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General (3 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General (4 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General (5 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General (6 of 7), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General (7 of 7), 1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “Aida”, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - “Emperor Jones”, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “Faust”, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “Old Man River”, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - “Pagliacci”, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jessie’s Manna Farms (1 of 5), 1935, 1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jessie’s Manna Farms (2 of 5), undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jessie’s Manna Farms (3 of 5), undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Jessie’s Manna Farms (4 of 5), undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Jessie’s Manna Farms (5 of 5), undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Funeral, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Music Manuscripts, 1892-1942, undated; 6
  This series contains Bledsoe's library of sheet music, much of which he used to sing in performances across the world. Many of the documents contain his handwritten notes.
  - Religious (1 of 2), undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Religious (2 of 2), undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Spirituals (1 of 5), 1917-1941, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Spirituals (2 of 5), 1917-1941, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Spirituals (3 of 5), 1917-1941, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Spirituals (4 of 5), 1917-1941, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Spirituals (5 of 5), 1917-1941, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Spirituals Books 1, 1905 (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Spirituals Books 2, undated (Box 9 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - General (1 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - General (2 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - General (3 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - General (4 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - General (5 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - General (6 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - General (7 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - General (8 of 8), 1899-1939, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - “Little Black Boy”, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - “I’m Troubled in Mind”, undated (Box 10 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - “Pickin’ Cotton”, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Song of the Mojave”, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - “If You Please”, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - “Figaros Hochzeit”, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - “Chloe”, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - De Glory Road” (1 of 2), undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - De Glory Road” (2 of 2), undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - General Books (1 of 3), 1919-1934 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - General Books (2 of 3), 1919-1934 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - General Books (3 of 3), 1919-1934 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Opera Sheet Music (1 of 3), 1901-1924, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Opera Sheet Music (2 of 3), 1901-1924, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Opera Sheet Music (3 of 3), 1901-1924, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - “L’Africaine” (1 of 2), undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - “L’Africaine” (2 of 2), undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - “L’Africaine” (2 of 2), undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Emporer Jones, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Music: Opera Books 1, 1897-1928, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Music: Opera Books 2, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Music: Opera Books 3, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Music: Opera Books 4, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Music: Opera Books 5, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Music: Opera Books 6, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Music: Opera Books 7, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Music: Opera Books 8, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Music: Opera Books 9, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Music: Opera Books 10, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Music: Opera Books 11, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Music: Opera Books 12, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Music: Opera Books 13, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Music: Opera Books 14, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Classical Sheet Music (1 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Classical Sheet Music (2 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Classical Sheet Music (3 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Classical Sheet Music (4 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Classical Sheet Music (5 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Classical Sheet Music (6 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Classical Sheet Music (7 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Classical Sheet Music (8 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 13 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Classical Sheet Music (9 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Classical Sheet Music (10 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Classical Sheet Music (11 of 11), 1898-1933, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Classical Books (1 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Classical Books (2 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Classical Books (3 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 14 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Classical Books (4 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Classical Books (5 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Classical Books (6 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Classical Books (7 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Classical Books (8 of 8), 1884-1914, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Patriotic (1 of 2), 1940-1942, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Patriotic (2 of 2), 1940-1942, undated (Box 15 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (1 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (2 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (3 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (4 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (5 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (6 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (7 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Composed or Arranged by Jules Bledsoe (8 of 8), 1939, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - "Bondage" (1 of 2), undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - "Bondage" (2 of 2), undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - “My Old Kentucky Home”, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Bledsoe Works: "The Good Old British Blue", undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Money in Kamben”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Fear I Aught”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Franky and Johnny”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Ode to America”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Hush Thee Baby”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Zulu Dance Song”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Legionnaire”, 1942, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Maybe He’s Your Boy in Khaki”, 1942, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Bledsoe Works: “Ole Man River”, undated (Box 19 OVZ, Folder 10)
- Oversize Materials, 1917, 1934-1943, 1978, undated; 7
  This series contains several oversize items, including several scrapbooks detailing Bledsoe's career. There is also a scrapbook about Bledsoe's funeral at Waco's New Hope Baptist Church.
  - Scrapbook (1 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook (2 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook (3 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook (4 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook (5 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook (6 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook (7 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook (8 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook (9 of 9), 1934-1943, undated (Box 16 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Funeral Scrapbook, 1943 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Guest Book, undated (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1943 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Posters, 1927 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1926, undated (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Diploma, 1917 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Plaque, 1978 (Box 20 OVZ)
- Media Recordings, undated; 8
  This series contains several tapes of Bledsoe singing several spiritual. Also included is a recording of Bledsoe singing his most well-known piece, "Ol' Man River."
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Cassette tape
  - Spirituals 1, undated (Item 1)
  - Spirituals 2, undated (Item 2)
  - Spirituals 3, undated (Item 3)